think like a
hacker yeah what did I just say think
like a hacker but not like the hacker
the way you think that you think what a
hacker is Think Like a hacker like oh I
don't know Aaron Schwarz and there's a
whole video on that it's linked from the
beginner boost who the hell is Aaron
Schwarz and is he really a
hacker I'm going to let you figure that
out on your own why would I say for you
to think like a hacker everybody's in
the studio audience why is it important
to learn to think like a hacker I just
throw stuff out throw stuff out I have
several bullet points that we're going
to make videos about but I want to hear
what you have to say
why why is learning to think like a
hacker going to make you a better
technologist and frankly a better human
being and when I'm talking about a
hacker I'm not talking about thinking
about how you're going to get rich by by
you know making the off of the suffering
of others I'm talking about the skills
to be a hacker what are the key skills
to be hacker and I guarantee you it's
not how to run metas sploid against a
Target the
key personality traits and the key
virtues if you will of hacking are the
things that make the best technologists
so let's like let's break it down and uh
we're not going to actually get
into um all of them now I'm just going
to kind of summarize them and then we'll
have videos where we're going to talk
about each of these because this is
really important before you even start a
Tech Career um you know what is a hacker
a a hacker ultimately and I made another
video about this but a hacker ultimately
is somebody who has really deep
knowledge of a particular system and to
quote from one of my favorite movies of
all
time right there is it even called the
movie would you call Mr Robot a
movie
Darlene says and there's a quote I'm GNA
mess it up but she
says uh Ellie she she comes she comes
she comes with a hack to to Ellie she
gives she's she's the malare writer for
their for their little you know posy and
she comes to she comes to to Elliot and
she hands off uh a USB
drive to to do a hack and I won't give
away the story and and Elliott says what
did you download this from 59 or some
you know and because she did it fast and
then she responds and she says look I
didn't have any time here and then she
says and I I'm going to screw the quote
up she says given enough time and white
papers I can run circles around any
system and I I know I I Slaughter that
but if you know where that episode is
you should go look it up somebody put
that in the comments and correct me on
on that but that quote is so relevant to
everything the reason darene is the
fictional but awesomest of all the
malware hackers is because she knows how
to learn she knows how to learn quickly
she knows where to go to get the
information she knows how to think about
how a system should be used and how it
can be used in ways that people may not
have thought of and that that is
thinking like a hacker thinking like a
hacker is taking a system and getting
deep knowledge of how the system works
so much so that you discover ways to use
the system that were not even designed
in the system itself that level of
exhaustive research and testing and
thinking outside the box I hate that
term but it thinking outside the box
outside the code Base outside the white
paper that is what makes you a kickass
hacker it's also what makes you the best
possible technologist because every time
you're making a system you're constantly
thinking what if somebody did this to it
what if somebody did this to it so
you're already making fantastic systems
whether you go into software engineering
making web apps or you're doing command
line Tooling in every single case you
are asking yourself all the time how can
this thing be you know how can I
somebody twist the arm of this thing to
use it in a different way for better or
worse and the thing that's really cool
about this is that if you start getting
into the habit of thinking alternatively
about the stuff that you've even made
you're going to find you're going to
find that you're going to see things in
the tools that you made value in the
tools that you made that wasn't even
there before you also see the
vulnerabilities in the tools that you
make but you're also going to see yeah
it just asn't inside the Box you're
going to see other things there that you
didn't even realize you made you're like
oh my God this is so great I can use it
for this other purpose I didn't even
know and I got my hoodie on today and
I'm going to just say it my one of my
getting becoming a good autodidact and
becoming a good technology professional
or good professional at all involves
understanding what your superpowers are
this is another video but one of my
personal
superpowers is seeing alternative usages
for things seeing how to get you know
around a thing and how to use it does
that make me a hacker I think it does I
think it just makes me a good
technologist honestly and and I don't I
don't consider myself a hacker per per
se and I did uh talk about a little bit
about my hacker experiences in the past
um and the thing is so interesting about
that is once you get into that mindset
you'll realize that you can do things
much more simply
than multi thousand software out there
that's been made to do the same thing
because they haven't thought about it so
developing this way of alternative
thinking and trying to you know find a
way to to to cause something to do
something it's not supposed to do that
is the formal definition of hacker by
the way it's not somebody who's going to
break in and destroy the world or you
know that's not it true the true
definition of hacker the original
definition of hacker is somebody who
takes a thing that's been designed for a
specific purpose and finds another way
to use it finds another way to cause it
to do something it's not intended to do
or combine it with other things to get
it to do things whether it be phone
freaking or you know Wi-Fi towers and
pineapples or or you know or or bikes
people hack bikes all the time in fact
there's um uh there's a there's a gcn
there's a whole thing called hacker
bodge you know like you people hack
things together using zip ties to make
their bikes work in different ways that
they weren't intended to that is hacking
hacking is the skill of finding
alternative uses for things and
understanding a thing more deeply than
even the the original uh white papers
may have described it that's it